Guide to the Mathew B. Brady and Levin Corbin Handy Photographic Studios Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Levin Corbin Handy Studio, 1849-circa 1956; Series II; (28 boxes)
  - Copy Photographs, (430 photographic prints)
    - Copy Photographs of Artwork and Mechanical Prints, (291 photographic prints)
      - Portraits
        - Lincoln, Abraham
          - Abraham Lincoln and his cabinet, engraving, (3 photographic prints) (Box 29, Folder 1439)
        - Lincoln, Mary Todd, lithograph, (2 photographic prints) (Box 29, Folder 1440)
        - Lincoln, Mary Todd, with William Lincoln and Thomas Lincoln, engraving after a photograph by P. Butler. Springfield, Illinois, (2 photographic prints) (Box 29, Folder 1441)
        - Lodge, Henry Cabot, painting by John Singer Sargent, 1890 (Box 29, Folder 1442)
          United States Senator from Massachusetts and United States Representative from Massachusetts
        - Long, Crawford Williamson, physician and pharmacist, engraving (Box 29, Folder 1443)
        - Macon, Nathaniel, painting by W. G. Randall, (2 photographic prints) (Box 29, Folder 1444)
          United States Representative from North Carolina, and United States Senator from North Carolina
        - Parker, Edgar, artist, engraving (Box 29, Folder 1445)
        - Poe, Edgar Allan, lithograph (Box 29, Folder 1446)
          After a daguerreotype probably made by Edwin H. Manchester at the Samuel Masury and Samuel W. Hartshorn studio in Providence, Rhode Island
        - Randolph, Peyton, painting (Box 29, Folder 1447)
        - Revere, Paul, painting by Charles Balthazar Julien Fevret de Saint-Memin, circa 1800 (Box 29, Folder 1448)
        - Roosevelt, Martha Bulloch, painting (Box 29, Folder 1449)
        - Scott, Dred, halftone of an oil painting by Louis Schultze, 1882 (Box 29, Folder 1450)
        - Standish, Myles, painting with a copyright held by Alfred S. Burbank (Box 29, Folder 1451)
        - Thomson, Charles, secretary of the Continental Congress, painting (Box 29, Folder 1452)
        - Van Ness, William Peter, second to Aaron Burr during his duel with Alexander Hamilton, painting (Box 29, Folder 1453)
        - Washington, Bushrod, and Annie Blackburn Washington, his wife (Box 29, Folder 1454)
          Bushrod Washington was an Associate Justice of the United States Supreme Court
        - Washington, George
          - George Washington and Augustine Washington. Father, I cannot tell a lie: I cut the tree, painted by G. G. Whiten, and lithograph engraved by John C. McRae (Box 29, Folder 1455)
          - George Washington, lithograph based on a painting by Charles Wilson Peale (Box 29, Folder 1456)
          - George Washington and his sister, Betty Washington Lewis, painting (Box 29, Folder 1457)
          - George Washington as a young child held by his mother, Mary Ball Washington, engraving (Box 29, Folder 1458)
          - George Washington riding a horse, painting (Box 29, Folder 1459)
          - George Washington and his family, by George Edward Perine, painting (Box 29, Folder 1460)
          - George Washington, engraving by D. Edwin after a painting by E. Bartoli (Box 29, Folder 1461)
          - George Washington, painting by Gilbert Stuart, (4 photographic prints) (Box 29, Folder 1462)
          - George Washington, painting by Rembrandt Peale (Box 29, Folder 1463)
          - George Washington, engraving by Laugier, 1839, based on a painting by Cogniet, 1836 (Box 29, Folder 1464)
        - Washington, Lawrence, painting by Gustavus Hesselius, circa 1738 (Box 29, Folder 1465)
        - Washington, Martha Dandridge Custis, painting by Eliphalet F. Andrews, 1878 (Box 29, Folder 1466)
        - White, John, painting (Box 29, Folder 1467)
          Speaker of the United States House of Representatives from Kentucky
        - Unidentified man, engraving (Box 29, Folder 1468)
        - Unidentified priest, painting, (2 photographic prints) (Box 29, Folder 1469)
        - Unidentified woman, miniature painting, (2 photographic prints) (Box 29, Folder 1470)
      - Caricatures
        - "Grave of the Union, or Major Jack Downing's Dream," drawn by Zeke, and lithograph published by Bromley & Co., New York, 1864, (2 photographic prints) (Box 29, Folder 1471)
        - "Jefferson Davis in his Wife's Clothes," engraving by Scattergood (Box 29, Folder 1472)
      - Composites
        - Abraham Lincoln and portraits of his pallbearers, composite of photographs (Box 29, Folder 1475)
        - Declaration of Independence, engraving by David Kimberly, published by Franklin Printing, Boston, 1841 (Box 29, Folder 1476)
        - Ferry on Anderson Creek, Indiana, and the first inauguration of Abraham Lincoln, Washington, District of Columbia, engravings (Box 29, Folder 1477)
        - George Washington and members of his cabinet, composite of photographs of paintings (Box 29, Folder 1478)
        - Thomas Jefferson and members of his cabinet, composite of photographs of paintings, (2 photographic prints) (Box 29, Folder 1479)
      - Texts
        - Advertisements for the Mutual District Messenger Company and Washington Nailor Cab Company (Box 29, Folder 1480)
        - Certificate electing George Washington President of the United States in the hand of John Langdon, 1789 Apr 6 (Box 29, Folder 1481)
        - Declaration of Independence, (12 photographic prints) (Box 29, Folder 1482)
        - Declaration of Independence (Box 29, Folder 1483)
        - Excerpts from George Alfred Townsend, "Still Taking Pictures," The World (New York; 12 April 1891) Page 26 (Box 29, Folder 1484)
          An interview with Mathew B. Brady
        - Gettysburg Address, last page, (2 photographic prints) (Box 29, Folder 1485)
        - Thanksgiving Day proclamation by George Washington, 1789 Oct 3 (Box 29, Folder 1486)
        - Letter from Abraham Lincoln to Secretary of the Interior, 1849 Jan 20 (Box 29, Folder 1487)
        - Letter from Abraham Lincoln to John Addison, 1850 Sep 9 (Box 29, Folder 1488)
    - Copy Photographs of Paintings of Signatories of the United States Declaration of Independence and the United States Constitution, (59 photographic prints)
      Arranged with signatories of the United States Declaration of Independence followed by signatories of the United States Constitution, and alphabetically within each heading by the surname of the subject.
      - Signatories of the United States Declaration of Independence
        - Braxton, Carter - Virginia delegate (Box 30, Folder 1489)
        - Carroll, Charles, of Carrollton - Maryland delegate (Box 30, Folder 1490)
        - Chase, Samuel - Delaware delegate (Box 30, Folder 1491)
        - Ellery, William - Rhode Island delegate (Box 30, Folder 1492)
        - Floyd, William - New York delegate (Box 30, Folder 1493)
        - Gwinnett, Button - Georgia delegate (Box 30, Folder 1494)
        - Hall, Lyman - Georgia delegate (Box 30, Folder 1495)
        - Hancock, John - Massachusetts delegate (Box 30, Folder 1496)
        - Hart, John - New Jersey delegate (Box 30, Folder 1497)
        - Hopkins, Stephen - Rhode Island delegate (Box 30, Folder 1498)
        - Lee, Francis Lightfoot - Virginia delegate (Box 30, Folder 1499)
        - Lee, Richard Henry - Virginia delegate (Box 30, Folder 1500)
        - Lewis, Francis - New York delegate (Box 30, Folder 1501)
        - Livingston, Philip - New York delegate (Box 30, Folder 1502)
        - Lynch, Thomas, Jr. - South Carolina delegate (Box 30, Folder 1503)
        - McKean, Thomas - Delaware delegate (Box 30, Folder 1504)
        - Nelson, Thomas, Jr. - Virginia delegate (Box 30, Folder 1505)
        - Paine, Robert Treat - Massachusetts delegate (Box 30, Folder 1506)
        - Penn, John - North Carolina delegate (Box 30, Folder 1507)
        - Ross, George - Pennsylvania delegate (Box 30, Folder 1508)
        - Stockton, Richard - New Jersey delegate (Box 30, Folder 1509)
        - Taylor, George - Pennsylvania delegate (Box 30, Folder 1510)
        - Thornton, Matthew - New Hampshire delegate (Box 30, Folder 1511)
        - Wilson, James - Pennsylvania delegate (Box 30, Folder 1512)
        - Wythe, George - Virginia delegate (Box 30, Folder 1513)
      - Signatories of the United States Constitution
        - Bassett, Richard - Delaware delegate (Box 30, Folder 1514)
        - Bedford, Gunning, Jr. - Delaware delegate, (5 photographic prints) (Box 30, Folder 1515)
        - Blair, John - Virginia delegate (Box 30, Folder 1516)
        - Blount, William - North Carolina delegate, (6 photographic prints) (Box 30, Folder 1517)
        - Broom, Jacob - Delaware delegate (Box 30, Folder 1518)
        - Dickinson, John - Delaware delegate (Box 30, Folder 1519)
        - Gilman, Nicholas, Jr. - New Hampshire delegate (Box 30, Folder 1520-1521)
        - Gorham, Nathaniel - Massachusetts delegate (Box 30, Folder 1522-1523)
        - Gorham, Nathaniel - Massachusetts delegate (Box 30, Folder 1524)
        - King, Rufus - Massachusetts delegate (Box 30, Folder 1525)
        - Mifflin, Thomas - Pennsylvania delegate (Box 30, Folder 1526)
        - Pinckney, Charles Cotesworth (C.C.) - South Carolina (Box 30, Folder 1527)
  - Oversize Photographs, (35 photographic prints)
    This series consists of oversize photographic prints that have dimensions in excess of 22 x 30 cm and do not fit into standard size document boxes.
    The series is arranged with oversize photographic prints of images from the Mathew B. Brady Studio printed by the studio, followed by images originally created by the Levin Corbin Handy Studio, an exhibition on the histories of each studio, and copy photographs.
    - Oversize Photographs of Mathew B. Brady Studio Images, (5 photographic prints)
      - District of Columbia, Washington
        - Pennsylvania Avenue SE from the United States Capitol Building (Box 31, Folder 1528)
        - United States Capitol Building, Abraham Lincoln addressing the crowd at his second presidential inauguration, 1865 Mar 4 (Box 31, Folder 1529)
      - Maryland, Sharpsburg. Abraham Lincoln with George B. McClellan and group of officers (Box 31, Folder 1530)
      - Unidentified location. Exterior portrait of George Washington Custis Lee, Robert E. Lee, Walter Taylor (Box 31, Folder 1531)
      - Studio portrait of Thomas Jonathan "Stonewall" Jackson (Box 31, Folder 1532)
    - Oversize Photographs from the Levin Corbin Handy Studio, (7 photographic prints)
      - Studio Portraits
        - Keifer, Joseph Warren (Box 31, Folder 1533)
          Speaker of the United States House of Representatives and United States Representative from Ohio
        - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano (Box 31, Folder 1534)
        - Story, William Wetmore, sculptor (Box 31, Folder 1535)
      - Exteriors
        - Virginia, Shellfield. Shellfield Resort, a panorama comprised of two photographic prints showing houses and cottages (Box 31, Folder 1536)
        - Composite of a man with the superimposed face of Ulysses S. Grant mounted on a horse, then superimposed on a view of City Point, Virginia (Box 31, Folder 1537)
    - Oversize Exhibit on Mathew B. Brady Studio and Levin C. Handy Studio, (17 photographic prints)
      Oversize photographic prints probably created circa 1935 by the daughters of Handy, Alice H. Cox and Mary H. Evans, for an exhibit on the studios of Mathew B. Brady and Levin Corbin Handy, as well as the history of Washington, D.C.
      Arranged alphabetically by the geographical location, and then by the surname of the subject.
      - District of Columbia, Washington
        - 7th Street NW and G Street NW, Smithsonian American Art Museum and the National Portrait Gallery (Box 31, Folder 1538)
        - Ford's Theatre. Interior. Collapse of the floor from the first floor looking southeast, 1893 Jun 10 (Box 31, Folder 1539)
        - Harewood Hospital. Soldiers in ranks on parade, possibly the 12th Michigan Infantry (Box 31, Folder 1540)
        - Lafayette Square Opera House, later Belasco Theater, 717 Madison Place NW (Box 31, Folder 1541)
        - Maryland Avenue SW between 7th Street SW and 9th Street SW (Box 31, Folder 1542)
        - Old Locks House, also known as the Old Canal House on Tiber Creek, southeast corner at the intersection of 17th Street SW and Constitution Avenue NW (Box 31, Folder 1543)
        - Pennsylvania Avenue NW, from Pershing Square toward the United States Capitol with the Old Post Office Building on the right, circa 1900 (Box 31, Folder 1544)
        - Union Station, circa 1907 (Box 31, Folder 1545)
        - Washington Monument with fish ponds in the foreground, circa 1895 (Box 31, Folder 1546)
        - Willard Hotel (Box 31, Folder 1547)
        - Winder Building, 600 17th Street NW (Box 31, Folder 1548)
      - Studio portraits
        - Boyd, Belle (Box 31, Folder 1549)
        - Brady, Juliette Handy, Mathew B. Brady, and Mrs. Hagerty née Brady (Box 31, Folder 1550)
        - Edward, Albert, Prince of Wales, and thirteen men, 1860 (Box 31, Folder 1551)
          Identified, standing from left to right, William Brodie, Major Teasdale, Captain Gray, Charles G. L. Eliot, Lord Lyons (British Ambassador to the United States), Earl Saint Germans, Albert Edward, Prince of Wales, Duke of Newcastle, G. D. Ingleheart, G. T. Jenner, Frederick Warre, Secretary to the Duke of Newcastle; Identified, sitting from left to right, Dr. Ackland, Hinchinbrook, General Bruce
        - Garfield, Lucretia Rudolph (Box 31, Folder 1552)
        - Keene, Laura (Box 31, Folder 1553)
          Stage name of Mary Frances Moss
        - Sartoris, Ellen "Nellie" Wrenshall Grant, and Algernon Charles Frederick Sartoris (Box 31, Folder 1554)
    - Oversize Copy Photographs of Photographs and Paintings, (6 photographic prints)
      Arranged alphabetically by the surname of the subject.
      - Jefferson, Thomas, painting by Gilbert Stuart (Box 31, Folder 1556)
      - Lee, Robert Edward
        - Robert Edward Lee mounted on his horse, Traveller, painting by Michael Miley in Lexington, Virginia (Box 31, Folder 1557)
        - Robert Edward Lee posed sitting on a fallen tree, painting by Carl Gutherz (Box 31, Folder 1558)
      - Lincoln, Abraham
        - Abraham Lincoln posed standing (Box 31, Folder 1559)
        - Abraham Lincoln, from an ambrotype taken by Preston Butler in Springfield, Illinois, 1860 Aug 13 (Box 31, Folder 1560)
      - Confederate army veterans at Lee Camp Hall on Confederate Memorial Day, 1906 (Box 31, Folder 1561)
  - Photographic Negatives, 817 photographic negatives, consisting of 375 glass negatives and 442 film negatives
    This series consists of photographic negatives created by the Levin Corbin Handy studio on glass and film mediums and formats.
    This series is arranged by mediums, first glass negatives by size and therein by subjects, then film negatives by size and therein by subjects, followed by oversize glass negatives that have dimensions in excess of 22 x 30 cm and do not fit into standard size boxes.
    - Glass Photographic Negatives - Lantern Slides, (72 glass negatives)
      Glass plate negatives for producing lantern slides of images that document persons and locations of the American Civil War created by photographers employed by the studio of Mathew B. Brady. Other images illustrate the patterns that animals use for camouflage and texts that document the career of Brady.
      - American Civil War
        - Georgia, Atlanta (Box 32, Folder 1562)
        - Georgia, Atlanta. Destruction of the ordinance train of John Bell Hood, 1864 (Box 32, Folder 1563)
        - Virginia, Bealeton. Regimental staff of 93rd New York, 1863 (Box 32, Folder 1564)
        - Virginia, Bull Run. Confederate fortification (Box 32, Folder 1565)
        - Unidentified locations
          - Building (Box 32, Folder 1566)
          - Camp scene (Box 32, Folder 1567)
          - Coastal fortification (Box 32, Folder 1568)
          - Cooking in camp (Box 32, Folder 1569)
          - Exploded shell (Box 32, Folder 1570)
          - Former Confederate fortifications (Box 32, Folder 1571)
          - Heavy gun in a fort (Box 32, Folder 1572)
          - Kitchen scene (Box 32, Folder 1573)
          - Mounted soldier near a pontoon bridge (Box 32, Folder 1574)
          - Pontoon wagons (Box 32, Folder 1575)
          - Steamer Chattanooga (Box 32, Folder 1576)
          - Steamer New York (Box 32, Folder 1577)
          - Winter quarters (Box 32, Folder 1578)
      - Animal Patterns for Camouflage
        - Bird on stalks (Box 32, Folder 1579)
        - Bird shape in spots (Box 32, Folder 1580-1581)
        - Bird shape, inverted (Box 32, Folder 1582)
        - Caterpillars (Box 32, Folder 1583)
        - Chicken (Box 32, Folder 1584)
        - Ducklings in brush (Box 32, Folder 1585)
        - Horse shape and zebra (Box 32, Folder 1586)
        - Perspective of a bird (Box 32, Folder 1587-1588)
        - Plymouth Rock Hen (Box 32, Folder 1589)
        - Ptarmigan, or Snow Chicken (Box 32, Folder 1590)
        - Skunk from the perspective of a mouse or cricket (Box 32, Folder 1591)
        - Snake (Box 32, Folder 1592)
        - Snake in grass (Box 32, Folder 1593-1594)
        - Snake in pattern (Box 32, Folder 1595)
        - Sphinx moth (Box 32, Folder 1596)
        - Spotted pattern (Box 32, Folder 1597)
        - Two bird shapes (Box 32, Folder 1598)
      - District of Columbia. Washington. Library of Congress (Box 32, Folder 1599)
      - Studio portraits
        - Kearny, Philip (Box 32, Folder 1600)
        - Lincoln, Abraham (Box 32, Folder 1601)
        - Miles, Nelson Appleton (Box 32, Folder 1602)
        - Unidentified officer (Box 32, Folder 1603)
      - Unidentified locations
        - Pagoda architecture (Box 32, Folder 1604)
        - Snow-covered mountains (Box 32, Folder 1605-1607)
      - Unidentified interiors
        - Chapel (Box 32, Folder 1608)
        - Corridor (Box 32, Folder 1609)
        - Counter display (Box 32, Folder 1610)
      - Composite of Franklin Delano Roosevelt and a view of Hyde Park, New York, for a memorial postage stamp (Box 32, Folder 1611-1612)
        One plate broken
      - Copy photographs
        - District of Columbia. Washington. Bonus Army Camp, an exterior portrait of Miller Son, 1932 (Box 32, Folder 1613)
        - Studio portrait. William Dorsey Pender (Box 32, Folder 1614)
        - Man (Box 32, Folder 1615)
        - Map. Philippines for a three-cent stamp, (2 glass negatives) (Box 32, Folder 1616-1617)
        - Woodcut of signers of the Declaration of Independence, including John Penn, Caesar Rodney, Matthew Thornton, Carter Braxton, John Hart, and John Morton (Box 32, Folder 1618)
      - Texts
        - Anthony's Photographic Bulletin, 114 (Box 32, Folder 1619)
        - Anthony's Photographic Bulletin, 115 (Box 32, Folder 1620)
        - Anthony's Photographic Bulleti n, 222 (Box 32, Folder 1621)
        - Anthony's Photographic Bulletin, Photographic Reminiscences of the Late War, No. 1, Page 212 (Box 32, Folder 1622-1623)
        - Anthony's Photographic Bulletin, Photographic Reminiscences of the Late War, No. 2, Page 311 (Box 32, Folder 1624)
        - C. Edwards Lester, M. B. Brady and the Photographic Art
          - Pages 36-37 (Box 32, Folder 1625)
          - Pages 38-39 (Box 32, Folder 1626)
          - Pages 40-41 (Box 32, Folder 1627)
        - Francis B. Carpenter, Six Months at the White House
          - Pages 36-37 (Box 32, Folder 1628)
          - Page 91 (Box 32, Folder 1629)
          - Page 92 (Box 32, Folder 1630)
          - Pages 92-93 (Box 32, Folder 1631)
        - Photographic Art Journal, Brady at the World's fair (Box 32, Folder 1632)
        - Photographic Art Journal, Brady Visiting Europe (Box 32, Folder 1633)
        - Photographic Art Journal, a poem about the Brady Studio (Box 32, Folder 1634)
        - Unidentified, page 140 (Box 32, Folder 1635)
      - Still life
        - Election medallion, Andrew Johnson for Vice-President (Box 32, Folder 1636)
        - Rosetta Stone (Box 32, Folder 1637)
        - Stone with inscriptions (Box 32, Folder 1638-1640)
    - Photographic Glass Negatives, 4" X 5", (124 glass negatives)
      Glass plate negatives that document locations in Bermuda, Virginia, and Washington, D.C., as well as studio portraits and copy photographs of drawings, engravings, and maps.
      - Bermuda, St. George's Island
        - Brick and wooden buildings, and a woman in the side yard (Box 33, Folder 1641)
        - Brick building (Box 33, Folder 1642-1645)
        - Brick building and cemetery (Box 33, Folder 1646-1647)
        - Building (Box 33, Folder 1648-1649)
        - Cemetery (Box 33, Folder 1650)
        - Inscription (Box 33, Folder 1651)
        - Men standing in boats (Box 33, Folder 1652)
        - Sundial (Box 33, Folder 1653)
        - Woman on a pier (Box 33, Folder 1654-1655)
      - District of Columbia, Washington
        - Bonus Army Camp. Exterior portrait of two men and two girls, Miller Son, Bonus Camp, 1932 (Box 33, Folder 1656)
        - Library of Congress. Two women in foreground (Box 33, Folder 1657)
        - Old Post Office Building (Box 33, Folder 1658)
        - United States Capitol Building (Box 33, Folder 1659)
        - United States Capitol Building. Exterior. Behind trees (Box 33, Folder 1660-1661)
        - Washington Monument (Box 33, Folder 1662-1665)
        - Washington Monument and a small stone building (Box 33, Folder 1666)
      - Virginia, Abingdon
        - Brick house (Box 33, Folder 1667)
        - Exterior portrait of a man and a woman near a spring (Box 33, Folder 1668)
        - Wooden building (Box 33, Folder 1669)
      - Virginia, Alexandria. Sailing ship on the water, identified as an Italian warship (Box 33, Folder 1670)
      - Virginia, Fairfax
        - Residence of Dr. William Gunnell, 10520 Main Street, 1863 Mar 9 (Box 33, Folder 1671)
          Location of the capture of Brigadier General Edwin H. Stoughton
        - Fairfax Courthouse (Box 33, Folder 1672)
        - Man in a field with brick house in the distance. (Box 33, Folder 1673)
          Location Captain John Quincy Marr was killed on June 1, 1861
        - Old Fairfax Courthouse (Box 33, Folder 1674-1675)
      - Virginia, Gunston Hall. Grave of George Mason (Box 33, Folder 1676)
      - Unidentified locations
        - Brick building (Box 33, Folder 1677-1680)
        - Brick building among trees (Box 33, Folder 1681)
        - Brick building on a street corner (Box 33, Folder 1682-1685)
        - Cemetery monument (Box 33, Folder 1686)
          Identified as the Force family monument, including family members Samuel S. Force and Marion E. Force
        - Church (Box 33, Folder 1687)
        - Derelict wooden building (Box 33, Folder 1688-1693)
        - Equestrian statue of George Washington (Box 33, Folder 1694)
        - Exterior portrait of Samuel Follin (Box 33, Folder 1695)
        - Exterior portrait of a woman posed standing (Box 33, Folder 1696)
        - Four-story brick building, possibly the residence of Charles Sumner (Box 33, Folder 1697)
        - Four-story brick building, possibly the residence of Joseph Philo Bradley (Box 33, Folder 1698)
        - House, possibly the residence of Commodore Porter (Box 33, Folder 1699-1700)
        - House, possibly the residence of John Slidell (Box 33, Folder 1701)
        - House, possibly the residence of Mrs. Logan (Box 33, Folder 1702)
        - Interior of an informal portrait of an infant (Box 33, Folder 1703)
        - Interior of a rocking crib (Box 33, Folder 1704)
        - Man posed sitting in front of double-doors of a brick building (Box 33, Folder 1705)
        - Memorial to General William Smallwood (Box 33, Folder 1706-1708)
        - Residences (Box 33, Folder 1709-1710)